<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Envixty&#39;s Hub</title>
	<link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Blogs on Envixty&#39;s Hub</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en-us</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 16:38:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	
	
	<item>
		<title>Switching over to Hugo</title>
		<link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/03-switching-to-hugo/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 16:38:01 -0400</pubDate>
		
		<guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/03-switching-to-hugo/</guid>
		<description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, It has been over two months since I last updated the website, You might be concerned but fear not, I am still here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been experimenting with linux over the past two months and my modern system is way different than the old system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I switched back from Doom Emacs to Neovim, I am back to using the terminal as my main way of interacting with the computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have switched to DWM as my main window manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all this change to the way I do things on the computer, it is only appropriate that I also switch the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-the-switch&#34;&gt;Why the switch&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainly, I wanted to stop using Emacs, To turn org into html, you need Emacs. I wanted to switch to regular HTML but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be bothered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, When I watched a Luke Smith Video, I discovered Hugo and I was fasinated with it, At first I thought it was just a Javascript framework, but it barely uses Javascript&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is actually based&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-hugo&#34;&gt;What is Hugo&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo is a static website generator. The way it works is that you write pages (like this one) in Markdown, and then Hugo converts it over to HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use themes to customize the way your Hugo Website is, (You can seperate the CSS File from the theme to the website static directory).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo also automatically generates an RSS Feed for your website, allowing people who want to check your blog to just subscribe to it in their RSS Reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also use Hugo serve to run a local instance of your Hugo website on your machine for testing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo is just more fit for making a website than ORG-EXPORT is&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>My Clay Pot Making Experience</title>
		<link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/02-the-pot-making-experience/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 16:25:03 -0400</pubDate>
		
		<guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/02-the-pot-making-experience/</guid>
		<description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, So during State Testing, I was bored after taking the test due to the fact that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t do anything after the test until everybody was done the Test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I discovered I liked making Clay Pots. This was due to the fact that the person in my Test Room was an Art Teacher. I liked how it allowed me to express my creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-first-clay-pot&#34;&gt;My First Clay Pot&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my First Clay Pot, I decided to make it a Pinch Pot, basically what I did was that I made a Sphere-Like Shape and from the top, I dug my thumb deeper to make a Clay Pot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Midway through making the Pot, something terrible happened. So apparently the Pot was too thick causing it to explode in the Kiln. I decided to keep going and make the Pot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Glaze, I added a Dark-Blue Colored Glaze, When applying the glaze, it looked like a light-purple color but then when it came out the kiln it was indeed Dark-Blue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a photo of the Pot:
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/clay_pot1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;pot-numero-dos&#34;&gt;Pot Numero Dos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the first Pot, I decided to make another Pot, I was doing the same thing and then I realized I was making a rectangle shape so I decided to make a small container.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had it in two parts, Part 1 was the container. Part 2 was a lid that went on top of the container.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a photo of the Pot (Doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the lid):
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/clay_pot2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-class-pot&#34;&gt;The Class Pot&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After these Clay Pots, I had gotten assigned to make a clay pot. The way we did it was a slab pot where You would make it peice by peice and then slip and score to make the Pot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What ended up happening when I tryed slipping and scoring the two ends of the walls was that the walls broke and they kept on breaking. I wanted a new clay slab for the walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I ended up doing was shaping the clay, and Slipping and Scoring the Plastic to the Pastic -&amp;gt; LeatherHard Clay that was the bottom and the handle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Glaze, I decided to use a bright red (it&amp;rsquo;s my favorite color). Turns out the Red Clay has a defect in that it isn&amp;rsquo;t as strong as the other clay, so instead of doing 3 coats. I had to do 5 coats with the red glaze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a photo of the Pot:
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/clay_pot3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the End, I really enjoyed making Clay Pots, I would recommend anybody who hasn&amp;rsquo;t made a clay pot to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yJTNmOYfVoI&#34;&gt;Here is a tutorial explaining how to make a Pinch Pot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>My Personal System</title>
		<link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/01-my-personal-system/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 16:10:31 -0400</pubDate>
		
		<guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/01-my-personal-system/</guid>
		<description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;operating-system&#34;&gt;Operating System&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Linux as my main Operating System&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes I know you are gonna say that it is infact &amp;ldquo;GNU/Linux&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know it is actually GNU/Linux&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Linux Distro I use is Arch Linux (btw): &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/arch.png&#34; alt=&#34;Arch Logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;FEATURES&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rolling Release (get newest software first)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Arch User Repository (Repo of user-made software)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Less Bloated (Less Software installed by default)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are new to linux, I would recommend installing a Distro like &lt;a href=&#34;https://linuxmint.org&#34;&gt;Linux Mint&lt;/a&gt; due to their ease-of-use&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;window-manager&#34;&gt;Window Manager&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://awesomewm.org&#34;&gt;AwesomeWM&lt;/a&gt; as my Window Manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;REASONS WHY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Configured in a real language (due to being configured in lua, you can do anything with this wm)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tiling (Instead of being floating where windows are ontop of other windows, this is tilied meaning windows are TILED next to other Windows, Improving Productivity)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Efficiency (This WM primary uses the keyboard instead of the mouse, Improving Productivity)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a screenshot of my AwesomeWM config:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/dotfiles1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Old Dotfiles&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;utilities&#34;&gt;Utilities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-utils&#34;&gt;Basic Utils&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my text editor, I have both &lt;a href=&#34;https://neovim.io&#34;&gt;Neovim&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/doomemacs/doomemacs&#34;&gt;Doom Emacs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/doomemacs/doomemacs&#34;&gt;Doom Emacs&lt;/a&gt; way more than Neovim&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;REASONS WHY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GUI (things like photo previews are possible)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Org-Mode (A comprehensive note-taking and website making tool)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Magit (TUI frontend for Git, easier to use than CLI git)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Doom Config (Makes it easier to manage config by splitting it)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my Terminal Emulator, I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://sw.kovidgoyal.net/kitty/&#34;&gt;Kitty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is why&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;REASONS WHY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GPU-POWERED (Allows terminal to be faster)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kittens (Python Programs for interacting with kitty)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advanced-utils&#34;&gt;Advanced Utils&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my system shell I use Dash&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the reasons why&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;REASONS WHY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Faster (This is due to it only being POSIX)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of using SUDO I use DOAS, this is because it is less bloated&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	</channel>
</rss>
